Yuki Matsuno Data Scientist







Japanese Data Scientist with expertise in data analysis using **Python**, **pandas**, and **machine/deep learning** models. I am excited by the incredible power of data science to make things possible that are impossible for humans. I am particularly interested in machine learning/deep learning, and CNN.

Professional Experience

2019 – present Tokyo	 Technical Support Specialist, Pearson Vue Co Ltd. Conduct technical troubleshooting on test servers via phone/remote control within the required SLA time Configuration or install software for front-end users who require assistance Program management, translating client guides, technical issue escalation
2018 – 2019	Working Holiday, Government of Canada
2019 Tokyo	 Network Infrastructure Engineer, Outsourcing Technology Co. Ltd Managing Interactive Voice Response systems (IVR) Mass scale DDI migration of telecom numbers in event of relocation

Data Science Projects

Crop classifier [App □], [Code □]

Developed a machine learning classifier to help mill owners optimize agribusiness by classifying satellite image files as rice or sugarcane

Dataset size: 9000+ satellite imagery

Method: KNN model, data engineering, pipeline (scaler, PCA), Confusion Matrix

E-commerce Service Optimization

Analysis for better customer experience and to maximize e-commerce company's profits. Gave a presentation.

Dataset size: 100k orders

Method: data frame creation, Statsmodels, OLS, visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn)

Education

2021	 LeWagon 6 Month Data Science Bootcamp, LeWagon Tokyo Received Special mention during LeWagon [Demo Day ☑]. [Demo ☑], [Code ☑] Learnt Machine Learning, Data Science, Python, SQL, Git, GitHub, Heroku Short Certifications: Ruby Foundations, Data Science Foundations 	
2009 – 2014	Bachelor of English and Literature, Prefectural University of Kumamoto	
	 GPA of 3.9 / 5, worked as freelance translator during and after university 	
	 Exchange Student to Montana State University, USA for 1 year 	

Data Science Skills

Data Mining	Machine Learning	Data Engineering	Cloud DevOps
Web Scraping, APIs,	Scikit-learn,	Python, SQL,	Heroku, GCP, Docker,
Python	TensorFlow, Pandas,	algorithms (KNN,	Git, Packaging Code
	Matplotlib, Python	Random Forest, SVM,	
		CNN, SGD)	